<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>John Woodman&#39;s Security Blog</title>
    <link>https://john-woodman.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on John Woodman&#39;s Security Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://john-woodman.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Week 14: The end (for now)</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-14/</guid>
      <description>More harvesting! The reason this is Week 14 is because I skipped blogging last week due to Thanksgiving. This week, I harvested more of the crops that were ready to be harvested. This included the pole beans and the green onions. In retrospect, the green onions were ready for a while, but I wanted to see how long I could get them (turns out, almost 1.5 ft long). Initally, I thought the pole beans would be ready when they turned solid green, but it turns out that they can stay a white color, as long as you can feel the hard bumps within the pod.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WADComs: Windows/Active Directory Interactive Cheat Sheet</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/research/wadcoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/research/wadcoms/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m hacking a Windows/AD environment, I spend a significant portion of my time looking at cheat sheets online or googling for various tools and commands that I forget (my memory kind of sucks). Not only that, but when I go to these cheat sheets, I&amp;rsquo;m always using control+F to find the exact command I&amp;rsquo;m looking for, often taking even more time and requiring me to visit multiple sites just to find the right command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regrow Project Part 4</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/regrow-project-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/regrow-project-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Gone, but not forgotten As I stated last week, my propagule was on the decline, and this week it met its end. I had transplanted it last week in hopes that it might just barely survive. This did not happen, however, and my celery gave its final breath. I&amp;rsquo;ve let it stay in the garden, since it can help fertilize the soil. It&amp;rsquo;s death shall help bring new life to future plants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 12: Cold</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-12/</guid>
      <description>Harvest Time! It&amp;rsquo;s finally time to reap what I sowed! As I mentioned last week, I was planning on harvesting my radishes and I did exactly that. I harvested 3 out of the 6 I had growing, since the other 3 still needs time to grow a bit more. Looking back, I probably could&amp;rsquo;ve waited another week or 2, but I was worried that they would be in the soil for too long and get spongy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regrow Project Part 3</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/regrow-project-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/regrow-project-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Propagule&amp;hellip;PropaDIE Unfortunately, this week was the demise of my propagule. I believe I left the celery in the propagule for too long, allowing for mold to grow around the roots. I should&amp;rsquo;ve transplanted it sooner to my garden. I ended up transplanting it anyway while the leaves were still green, but it was too late. The leaves have begun wilting, and will no doubt become fertilizer in the next coming days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 11: Stake</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-11/</guid>
      <description>Supporting My Plants This week, I focused on learning about organic gardening and finally stopping my pole beans from killing all my other plants. Something interesting I learned is that technically I haven&amp;rsquo;t been doing &amp;ldquo;official&amp;rdquo; organic gardening, because actual organic gardening needs to be certified by the USDA on a yearly basis. Either way, I&amp;rsquo;m having a lot of fun with my unofficial organic gardening. Now to talk about stopping my pole beans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regrow Project Part 2</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/regrow-project-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/regrow-project-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Propagule&amp;hellip;PropaGROW This week, I checked in on my celery propagule I had planted last week, and it seems to be doing really good so far! About 5 leaves have started to grow from the propagule and have a bright green color to them. Small roots have begun to grow from the bottom of the propagule that was submerged in the water of the cup. The propagule around the outside has begun to get moldy in small spots, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think that will be a big issue once I transplant the propagule to the garden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 10: Defending My Plants</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-10/</guid>
      <description>Checking for Insects This week, I took a closer look at the plants in my garden for any potential insects that could be harming my plants. Luckily (or potentially unluckily [is that even a word]) I didn&amp;rsquo;t find any insects or damages to the leaves of any of the plants currently thriving in the garden. I do have a small bottle of soap insecticide, so in the future if there are any, I will mix that with a little bit of water and just spray onto the insects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regrow Project</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/regrow-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/regrow-project/</guid>
      <description>Regrowing Celery This week, I started the process of regrowing celery from a propagule. A propagule is just a term used to define the part of the plant used to regrow said plant. In this case, it&amp;rsquo;s the bottom part of the celery. I cut about 2 inches above the root of the celery. I then used a red solo cup and 4 toothpicks to hold up the propagule. I stuck holes in the red solo cup for the toothpicks to go through, and then inserted them into the celery propagule.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 9: Mystery</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-9/</guid>
      <description>Microgreens This week, I started germinating microgreens. The seeds sent by my professor were labelled &amp;ldquo;mystery&amp;rdquo; so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what microgreens I&amp;rsquo;m actually growing, which makes things interesting. To germinate the microgreens, I recycled a strawberry container that I had lying around (definitely didn&amp;rsquo;t just buy strawberries for the container). I then placed a fiber pad in the container, and soaked it thoroughly in water. I scattered the mystery seeds onto the fiber pad, placing them close together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 8: Hydro</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-8/</guid>
      <description>Upgrades This week I built a hydroponic system for my lettuce seedling. I used an empty 2 Liter bottle of sprite, cutting the upper third off with scissors and poking a hole in the bottle cap. I then put cotton wick through the hole in the bottle cap and tied a knot so it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t fall out. I then added half a liter of water, 3 drops of vinegar, and 1/4 teaspoon of dissolvable fertilizer to the bottom of the bottle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2020-26894 Privilege Escalation Vulnerability in LiveCode v9.6.1 Programming Language</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/research/livecode-privilege-escalation-vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/research/livecode-privilege-escalation-vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>Summary LiveCode v9.6.1 for Windows is vulnerable to a horizontal privilege escalation vulnerability.
CVE Mitre Assigned: CVE-2020-26894
Discovery While taking a Wildlife Issues course at my University, I discovered a high severity vulnerability in the course software our class was using that leads to a horizontal privilege escalation.
At first, I thought the vulnerability was only in this course software, but looking into it deeper and with the help of one of the developers at faulkner press, we discovered that the vulnerability actually lied in the programming language/framework they were using: LiveCode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 7: Plant Food</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-7/</guid>
      <description>Transplanting! This week I transplanted my bell pepper and basil seedlings. The bell pepper seedling&amp;rsquo;s roots were starting to stick out of the peat pellet, so I knew it was time to move to the main garden. The basil seedlings probably could&amp;rsquo;ve stayed inside for a few more days, but I think they&amp;rsquo;ll be fine (knock on wood). I placed them in one of the corners of the garden, about 12 inches away from each other, making sure to water them thoroughly once transplanted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 6: Pinch</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-6/</guid>
      <description>Casualty One of my bell pepper seedlings has unfortunately suffered a casualty. While on the window sill, the blinds fell directly onto my germination station, cutting one of the bell pepper seedlings in half. All that remains is the stem. I&amp;rsquo;ve left it there and have continued to water it in hopes that it may still survive. RIP for now, bell pepper seedling. Forever in our hearts.
Almost Ready To Transplant Other than the one casualty, my other basil and bell pepper seedlings are looking really good!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 5: Irrigation</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-5/</guid>
      <description>Everything is Growing! One of my onions finally sprouted and is visible through the soil! It&amp;rsquo;s now official: every type of plant I&amp;rsquo;ve sowed has sprouted! The radishes and pole beans sprouted very quickly, much quicker than any of the others had. My garden is starting to look more and more like a garden everyday :). The sunflowers are still the tallest, but they&amp;rsquo;ve started drooping a little, so I&amp;rsquo;ll have to keep a watch on them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 4: Outdoor</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-4/</guid>
      <description>They&amp;rsquo;re Growing! Quite a lot happened this past week. After watering the seeds I planted daily, some of them broke ground! The sunflowers were the first to come up, growing way faster than any of the others. The basil was the next to come, still inside the peat pellets. Then, just a couple days ago, the zinnia broke through! The onion starters still haven&amp;rsquo;t broken through yet, but I&amp;rsquo;m guessing those take longer to grow than the others, given the size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 3: Germination</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-3/</guid>
      <description>Germination This week I finally started germinating my seeds. This is something I&amp;rsquo;ve never done before, so the whole process was very new to me. I started planting the following seeds:
 Bell Peppers Zinnia Sun Flowers Basil Onion starters  I germinated the bell peppers and basil seeds in peat pellets, which I placed indoors inside of an egg carton. This will allow it to grow enough to be transplanted to the main garden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 2: Green Thumb</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-2/</guid>
      <description>My Background This is my first time gardening, and actually my first time dealing with any sort of plant care, so I&amp;rsquo;m very new to this, but also very excited to learn. I&amp;rsquo;ve always sort of imagined my older self having a small garden in my backyard where I would grow food that I would use for my meals, being as environmentally friendly as I could. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this class will be a good introduction for me, and help me better understand the works that will go in to maintaining a garden.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 1: Salad Inventory</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/gardening/week-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Welcome to my first gardening blog post. I plan on documenting my progress as I begin learning and growing my own 2.5ft x 2.5ft garden. This week to help me learn more about the different parts of a plant, I will be documenting an inventory of the last salad I ate, picking out which parts of the salad were leaves, flowers, roots, stems, or fruits.
Salad Inventory Below is a list of everything that was in my last salad, classified by their botanical definition:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackerTwitter: Simple UI Design for Twitter</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/research/hacker-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/research/hacker-twitter/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t like how cluttered twitter&amp;rsquo;s feed is all the time and much prefer ycombinator&amp;rsquo;s Hacker News design. So I created a twitter UI that lets you view your timeline with a ycombinator type feel to it. I have a running instance you can sign into and if you don&amp;rsquo;t trust me, you can view the source code for it as well (links below). Enjoy :)
HackerTwitter: https://twitter.john-woodman.com/
GitHub Repo: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up Your Own Malicious DNS Server For Data Exfiltration (Without a DNS Server)</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/research/dns-exfiltration-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/research/dns-exfiltration-setup/</guid>
      <description>Data exfiltration is a key component of any red team/penetration testing assesment. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s as simple as scp&amp;rsquo;ing the sensitive data over an SSH connection. Other times, however, more sophisticated methods need to be used. One such common method is exfiltrating data through specially crafted URL requests to your public web server, such as placing the sensitive data as a GET parameter (www.evil.com?stolendata=password123). But what if firewall permissions are blocking any outbound HTTP traffic on the victim server?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackTheBox: Writeup</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/writeups/htb-writeup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/writeups/htb-writeup/</guid>
      <description>Box Type: Linux Getting User Nmap scan showed ports 22 and 80 open. Checking out the website shows a notification that some sort of DoS protection is running on the webserver, likely preventing any dictionary or brute force attacks, which means no dirb :(. The Nmap scan did show a robots.txt, however: Navigating to /writeup shows a home page with writeups for other retired boxes: Using wappalyzer, it showed that this webpage was running &amp;ldquo;CMS Made Simple&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Most Fun (and maybe impractical) Command and Control: SpotifyC2</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/research/spotifyc2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/research/spotifyc2/</guid>
      <description>Command and Control is one of the most common techniques used by attackers to maintain persistent control over an infected computer, sending commands to be executed and receiving the output of those commands. There exists many different methods for implementing Command and Control, from using cloud services (AWS, Azure, etc.) to even using social media to send commands. One method we will be exploring is one I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen before (probably for a good reason): using Spotify to send commands and receive output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VBA Macro Remote Template Injection With Unlinking &amp; Self-Deletion</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/research/vba-macro-remote-template-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/research/vba-macro-remote-template-injection/</guid>
      <description>One of the most common methods leveraged by attackers is the use of Malicious Word/Excel Documents sent over email. These malicious docs are embedded with macro VBA code that, when run, execute various tasks on the victim’s computer, usually resulting in RCE (Remote Code Execution) and/or data exfiltration.
There are numerous techniques used on these malicious docs to bypass anti-virus detection (VBAStomping, obfuscation, etc.). One such method is Remote Template Injection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://john-woodman.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://john-woodman.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a security enthusiast looking for new ways to break stuff and stay hidden while doing it. All content posted here is for educational and research purposes only.
Contact  john.woodman11@gmail.com @JohnWoodman15 GitHub  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
